<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>blog &#8211; Adam Horne: Selected Works (200X — 2020)</title>
	<atom:link href="https://adamhorne.com/tag/blog/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://adamhorne.com</link>
	<description>I’m driven by curiosity. And fear. And money.</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Jul 2020 19:04:25 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.5</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://adamhorne.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/cropped-android-chrome-512x512-1-32x32.png</url>
	<title>blog &#8211; Adam Horne: Selected Works (200X — 2020)</title>
	<link>https://adamhorne.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>#6 Reasons Why Case Study Videos Shouldn&#8217;t Be The Cornerstone Of Your First Portfolio</title>
		<link>https://adamhorne.com/6-reasons-why-cast-study-videos-suck-a-bit/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Adam Horne]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 27 Jul 2020 19:02:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blog]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://adamhorne.com/?p=949</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[#1 CASE STUDY VIDEOS WALLPAPER OVER THIN CAMPAIGN THINKING AND EXECUTION Lots of case study videos that I see are for small, tactical, or inconsequential things. They’re rarely for big campaign thoughts that execute over time and touchpoints. #2 THE REPLACE A CAMPAIGN AUDIENCE WITH A CASE STUDY AUDIENCE The audience for these videos are [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><strong>#1 CASE STUDY VIDEOS WALLPAPER OVER THIN CAMPAIGN THINKING AND EXECUTION</strong></p>



<p>Lots of case study videos that I see are for small, tactical, or inconsequential things. They’re rarely for big campaign thoughts that execute over time and touchpoints.</p>



<p><strong>#2 THE REPLACE A CAMPAIGN AUDIENCE WITH A CASE STUDY AUDIENCE</strong></p>



<p>The audience for these videos are the creative industry. So young creatives get good at highlighting things that impress them, and don’t take to real people.</p>



<p><strong>#3 CREATIVE WORK IS ONLY FINISHED ENOUGH TO ANIMATE INTO A CASE STUDY VIDEO</strong></p>



<p>Because the actual work exists fleetingly on screen, the actual creative product is rarely refined enough to go into the world. So it’s often either naive, impossible, or just half-assed.</p>



<p><strong>#4 THEY ENCOURAGE SOLVING LITTLE THINGS BY FRAMING THEM AS BIGGER THINGS</strong></p>



<p>Instead of executing on big strategy with big bold stuff, it’s the communication equivalent of a Ph.D &#8211; zooming in and in on an area that becomes inconsequential to almost everyone.</p>



<p><strong>#5 THEY TAKE LOTS OF TIME TO MAKE. TIME THAT COULD BE BETTER USED ELSEWHERE</strong></p>



<p>I want to see young creatives with portfolios bursting with ideas that cross a huge range of products, services, and audiences. But because they take so long to get right, you often only see 3-6 things in a portfolio. So those few things become tight, overworked, and a little lifeless.</p>



<p><strong>#6 THEY’RE MOSTLY MORE PREDICTABLE THAN THE WORK THEY CONVEY</strong></p>



<p>Sure, some case study videos are as creative as the work they communicate. But most follow a lazy format of problem &gt; insight &gt; “what if &gt; “introducing” &gt; turns out… It’s a little self-defeating if you want to convince someone that you look at familiar things in creative new ways.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>From many, one. Choosing the right creative concept.</title>
		<link>https://adamhorne.com/choosing-a-creative-concept/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Adam Horne]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2019 18:46:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blog]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://adamhorne.com/?p=866</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It should be easy, instinctive, and stress-free. How hard can it be to choose the best concept? In my experience, it’s very challenging. It&#8217;s also where many tool-kits, processes, and systems defer back to you. However, it’s one of the most critical parts of a successful campaign. And you&#8217;re on your own. According to Harvard [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><strong>It should be easy, instinctive, and stress-free. How hard can it be to choose the best concept? In my experience, it’s very challenging.  It&#8217;s also where many tool-kits, processes, and systems defer back to you. </strong></p>



<p>However, it’s one of the most critical parts of a successful campaign. And you&#8217;re on your own. According to Harvard Business Review, “a euro invested in a highly creative ad campaign had nearly double the sales impact of a euro spent on a non-creative campaign.”<a href="#_ftn1"><sup>[1]</sup></a></p>



<p>In many ways it’s more difficult selecting the right idea than it is having the right idea. Here is some advice for helping you choose the right creative concept.</p>



<p><strong>Get
clear</strong></p>



<p>Give yourself some time between any concept
development you and your team have done and choosing your creative campaign.
Even a day or two will help make decisions about the merits of the work much
more manageable.</p>



<p><strong>The
SMP and creative brief will guide you</strong></p>



<p>Your original creative brief is the best
single document you have by which to measure creative concepts. Ask yourself
the following questions:</p>



<ul><li>Does the creative concept deliver on the single-minded proposition
(SMP), or is it communicating something different?</li><li>Can the creative concept be executed faithfully and powerfully in
the channels we’ve selected?</li><li>Can it be executed well given the constraints of our budget and
timeline?</li><li>Is it rewarding for your audience or a waste of their time?</li></ul>



<p><strong>Understand
your different audience and their needs</strong></p>



<p>It’s very important that when developing
your campaign, you keep in mind the fact that you will need to develop three
suites of communication, for your three audiences. It’s very easy to develop a
creative concept that favours one of your audiences and compromises the others.
Keep this in mind when making your decision. </p>



<p><strong>Seek
opinions</strong></p>



<p>It’s essential to get new perspectives on
creative concepts. It will help mitigate problems you’re blind to and help you
see the work from more subjective positions. However, when confronted, many
people feel the need to react rationally, that is, in a way that can be
logically defended. To critique work logically is to deny the emotive qualities
of a creative concept. Stay mindful of this.</p>



<p>It’s also a good idea to ask your audience
what they think. The power of the creative concept to affect change in your
audience is, in conclusion, the only thing that matters. You can do this with
focus groups or surveys, but again, you risk your audiences reacting rationally
to work and thus skewing the analysis. A better way is to test campaign
elements in context and in-market.</p>



<p><strong>Accept
the impossibility of a perfect decision</strong></p>



<p>You must choose the creative concept that
you think and feel will be the most effective. It’s a decision made with
imperfect information. However, it’s better to choose a good creative concept
earlier than a better creative concept later. That’s because the quality of the
idea is only as good as the execution of the idea, and all ideas take more time
to execute well that you might initially think.</p>



<p><strong>Shun
democracy</strong></p>



<p>Democracy might feel like a fair way of
choosing a creative concept, but generally, it’s at the expense of an effective
campaign. Groups of people tend to select creative concepts that nobody hates.
Which is to say they choose things that very few people are captivated by. It’s
better to choose a creative campaign that people react strongly to (hopefully
positively), than a campaign that’s easy to ignore. Don’t forget that you’re
primarily fighting for attention.</p>



<p><strong>It
extends painlessly</strong></p>



<p>One typical quality of good creative
campaign is their ability to extend out into all media, platforms, executions,
and audiences. If a concept works well from long-form video, Instagram posts,
press releases, etc. and can be executed for professionals as well as the
public, then you should feel confident that your creative concept is in fact, a
creative platform for your entire campaign.</p>



<p><strong>It’s
refreshing</strong></p>



<p>Your creative concept should not be
entirely predictable. It should challenge the conventions of the public-health
category if it’s to get the attention it deserves. Nobody on the internet is
looking to engage with predictable and uninspired content or communication.
Respect your audience and don’t burden them with boring.</p>



<p><strong>It’s
a bit scary</strong></p>



<p>If it doesn’t feel a little bit dangerous,
then you might be backing a creative concept that’s so safe that it might be
ineffective. However, support yourself. Choose a strong creative concept and
then move your attention into execution it with confidence.</p>



<p><strong>Don’t
create a monster</strong></p>



<p>When considering the merits of different
creative concepts, it’s common to want to take the best parts of different
concepts and Frankenstein them into a new campaign. That is almost always a bad
idea and yields a confusing mix of ideas that all compromise each other.
Instead, choose one idea and do it well. Or else you’ll burden your audience
with a horse-cat, dog-pony, of whale-goat.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator"/>



<p><a href="#_ftnref1"><sup>[1]</sup></a> https://hbr.org/2013/06/creativity-in-advertising-when-it-works-and-when-it-doesnt</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>At Berghs</title>
		<link>https://adamhorne.com/at-berghs/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Adam Horne]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2019 10:19:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blog]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://adamhorne.com/?p=821</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Note: This originally appeared on Berghs site. Here&#8217;s a streamlined version (that gives you the vibe of Berghs School of Communication. To crack the code on what sets Berghs apart from the competition Sarah Snavely talks to Adam Horne, Creative Director of Berghs Studio. How would you describe the Berghs’ way of teaching? Adam: It’s [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><em>Note: This originally appeared on </em><a rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label="Berghs site (opens in a new tab)" href="https://www.berghs.se/artiklar/at-berghs-the-world-is-our-classroom-creativity-our-guide/" target="_blank"><g class="gr_ gr_5 gr-alert gr_gramm gr_inline_cards gr_run_anim Grammar multiReplace" id="5" data-gr-id="5"><em><g class="gr_ gr_211 gr-alert gr_gramm gr_inline_cards gr_run_anim Grammar only-ins replaceWithoutSep" id="211" data-gr-id="211">Berghs</g></em></g><em> site</em></a><em>. Here&#8217;s a streamlined version (that gives you the vibe of Berghs School of Communication.</em></p>



<p><strong>To crack the code on what sets Berghs apart from the competition Sarah Snavely talks to Adam Horne, Creative Director of Berghs Studio.</strong></p>



<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" width="1024" height="768" src="https://adamhorne.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/nils-1024x768.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-823" srcset="https://adamhorne.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/nils-1024x768.jpg 1024w, https://adamhorne.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/nils-300x225.jpg 300w, https://adamhorne.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/nils-768x576.jpg 768w, https://adamhorne.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/nils-1568x1176.jpg 1568w, https://adamhorne.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/nils.jpg 2000w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure></div>



<p><strong>How would you describe the Berghs’ way of teaching?</strong></p>



<p>Adam: It’s a balance between being deeply pragmatic and deeply engaged with what the world needs now and in the immediate future, and the larger machinations that affect communication – namely cultural context and human psychology. </p>



<p><strong>What is action-based learning?</strong></p>



<p>Adam: Lots of things. It’s learning by doing. And it’s based on the understanding that nothing is right the first time. That pragmatic test-and-learn is a good pathway to a great result. It’s a way to get both sides of the brain working cohesively and an inviting way to learn. It’s also good fun.</p>



<p><strong>How does the Berghs’ method differ from that taught at other communication schools?</strong></p>



<p>Adam: Berghs is a pretty accurate reflection of its context. As an Australian, I really notice just how Swedish it is – in a good way! It’s a wonderful advantage in lots of ways. It’s less hierarchal. It’s more open to questioning itself – by both staff and students. It’s also practical. It’s not about looking smart, it’s about being smart. And it’s full of people with a real social conscience. And by not being a research school saves a whole lot of academic distraction.</p>



<p><strong>What sets Berghs apart from the competition?</strong></p>



<p>Adam: It’s so well established in the communication industry in Sweden that we attract the best people. Our teaching staff is world class – our students are world class. That the quality of the students is high is really a key – they drive each other more than the staff ever could. We’re also careful that we don’t get lazy or complacent. We work hard to keep our education and ideas fresh.</p>



<p><strong>Did the Berghs’ method evolve over time? What was learning like at Berghs when the school first opened in 1941?</strong></p>



<p>Adam: Articulating their value to business, in the language of business, will continue to be a huge issue. I think design thinking helped position creativity as a strategic business advantage, but there’s still a lot to do there. There are also structural shifts toward the gig economy, which can be very good mid-career but can rob grads of long-term exposure to mentors. You really need to keep learning in your first few jobs, and have role models to help you.</p>



<p><strong>Is there anything about the Berghs’ method of teaching that is specifically Swedish?</strong></p>



<p>Adam: Absolutely! As a society, it’s really flat. Students question everything. That’s pretty powerful. Also as a capital city, Stockholm is pretty quiet. People mainly leave you alone. And that’s really good for digging in and learning.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Junos Recycled Links: Ecology in Sweden</title>
		<link>https://adamhorne.com/junos-recycled-links/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Adam Horne]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2019 09:06:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blog]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.adamhorne.com/?p=796</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Right! Among the empty rhetoric, virtue signalling, and lazy consensus that environmental issues seem to generate, some really interesting things are happening here in Sweden.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><strong>I’m Adam, an Australian who’s pretty new in Sweden. </strong><br></p>



<p><strong>Being the new guy in town is a great chance to see a new society as an outsider. </strong><br></p>



<p>It’s a really fun place to be and I really do love it here. It’s certainly weird. But all countries are weird in their own way. It’s what makes the world interesting.<br></p>



<p>Right! Among the empty rhetoric, virtue signalling, and lazy consensus that environmental issues seem to generate, some really interesting things are happening. <br></p>



<p>Something else that’s interesting here is an indoor farming initiatives like <a href="http://odlandestadsbasarer.se/">Odlande stadsbasarer</a>. It seems pretty smart to turn urban space into places that grow food in really controlled conditions so you reduce the time and transport impact on food. Another reason why self-driving cars are a great idea &#8211; we can <a href="https://mothership.sg/2019/03/urban-farming-ang-mo-kio-car-park/">start</a> using <a href="https://futurecitiesandenvironment.com/articles/10.5334/fce.50/">carparks</a> to grow food. Right now it’s just hipster chic but hopefully it scales to a meaningful size.<br></p>



<p>Swedes sure seem to love to stand in the snow to separate their recycling! Personally, it drives me crazy. Of course we should recycle our stuff (duh). But there are <a href="https://www.popsci.com/technology/article/2013-07/how-it-works-recycling-machines-separate-junk-type">machines that do this automatically</a>. The cynic in me thinks it’s actually the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/IKEA_effect">IKEA effect</a> in action, that people feel more connected to things they engage actively in &#8211; and it seems to work. But it makes my hands cold and we need to make it easier to be good.<br></p>



<p>Is <a href="https://www.nudiejeans.com/">Nudie</a> still cool? Who knows! But you should be proud to call them Swedish. Everyone talks a big game (I’ve worked for some big denim brands) but they seem generally interested in moving to <a href="https://www.nudiejeans.com/blog/100-organic-maria-has-the-word">100% organic cotton</a>, selling <a href="https://www.nudiejeans.com/page/re-use">second hand jeans</a>, and <a href="https://www.nudiejeans.com/page/free-repairs-for-life">fixing their jeans</a> for free. And as a cyclist who’s always blowing their ass out of their jeans, I’m super into that!<br></p>



<p>And if you think about it, <a href="https://www.systembolaget.se/sok-dryck/?subcategory=R%C3%B6tt%20vin&amp;combinedcountry=Australien&amp;fullassortment=1">Systembolaget</a> is also essentially pretty green. By closing their doors on <a href="https://hejsweden.com/en/the-swedes-and-alcohol-about-drinking-in-sweden/">Saturday at 3pm</a>, I’m sure they reduce the amount of glass and aluminium packaging we’d otherwise consume. And that’s gotta be a good thing for Mother Earth, our credit cards, and our livers. Just kidding. Systembolaget should be <a href="https://www.thelocal.se/20060913/4884">sued</a> by the EU for being anti-competitive.  <br></p>



<p>Now who needs a drink? Tweet me at <a href="https://twitter.com/adamhorne">@adamhorne</a> if you do <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.0/72x72/1f642.png" alt="🙂" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> </p>



<p class="has-small-font-size"><em>This first appeared in <a href="http://junopr.se/recycled-links/">Junos Recycled Links</a> in an edited form.</em><br></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Apple: Staying Smart</title>
		<link>https://adamhorne.com/apple-staying-smart/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Adam Horne]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2019 19:41:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blog]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://adamhorne.com/?p=690</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[TL;DR &#8211; The future of computing is smarter, cloud based services, running on commodity hardware. Not expensive hardware running integrated software. Apple is not positioned well for this. But maybe the power of their brand can save them. Using an explanation of Apple’s assets, boundaries, and narrative, I’ll explain why it&#8217;s causing them to make [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><strong>TL;DR  &#8211; The future of computing is smarter, cloud based services, running on  commodity hardware. Not expensive hardware running integrated software.  Apple is not positioned well for this. But maybe the power of their  brand can save them.</strong></p>



<p>Using an explanation of Apple’s assets, 
boundaries, and narrative, I’ll explain why it&#8217;s causing them to make 
huge missteps when it comes to preempting the future of computing.</p>



<p><strong>Apple’s Assets:</strong></p>



<ul><li>The world’s most valuable company has a veritable riches of assets. They include:</li><li>A reputation of being the best designed objects in computing</li><li>A reputation of solving complicated technical and interface problems in the most humanistic way</li><li>The world’s most sophisticated production supply chain, capable of developing beautifully designed objects, at huge scale</li><li>A reputation for being high-desirable consumer electronics that convey high levels of social status</li><li>A reputation and long history of integrating hardware and software effortlessly</li><li>An instinct for taking immature technology and creating products that revolutionize the category</li><li>A reputation and history of protecting user data and privacy above all else</li><li>A network of retail stores where consumers can fixate upon, and fix, their products</li><li>An increasing reputation as a fashion brand</li></ul>



<p><strong>Apple’s Boundaries</strong></p>



<ul><li>Never use personally recognizable data to train machine learning systems</li><li>Never compete on price and become a commodity player</li><li>Maintain high profit margins and price per unit numbers</li><li>Lower design or manufacturing standards</li><li>Champion anything other than reductive and minimal design</li><li>Make large acquisitions and blend corporate culture</li><li>Invest heavily in things that don’t quickly develop into products</li><li>Not compelled to enter every market</li><li>A commitment that all Apple products reinforce the Apple ecosystem</li></ul>



<p><strong>Apple’s Narrative</strong></p>



<p>To discover Apple’s narrative, it helps to look at how they define their mission statement.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>&#8220;Apple
 is committed to bringing the best personal computing experience to 
students, educators, creative professionals and consumers around the 
world through its innovative hardware, software and Internet offerings.&#8221;</p></blockquote>



<p>I
 think internally they see their mission statement as “By making 
difficult decisions on behalf of users and carefully curating the 
experience, Apple is committed to bringing the best personal computing 
experience to students, educators, creative professionals and consumers 
around the world through its innovative hardware, software and Internet 
offerings[Italics added]”</p>



<p><strong>This exposes a clear gap between:</strong></p>



<ul><li>Industry
 trends, which place a lot of faith in machine learning systems trained 
with user data to become smarter and more useful as personal assistant 
ser</li><li>User’s real world approach to privacy, which is strict when 
asked, and soft when it comes to forgoing services that use their data 
(Facebook, Google, etc)</li><li>Apple’s raison d&#8217;etre, to “bringing the best personal computing experience”</li><li>I
 think the companies that best exploit machine learning, and develop 
artificial intelligence, peripheral to personal devices, will have the 
brightest future.</li></ul>



<p>I don’t think Apple are well poised to capitalize on this.</p>



<p><em>This is a piece I wrote as part of my <a target="_blank" href="https://altmba.com/" rel="noreferrer noopener">altMBA program</a>.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Online Advertising: Defending Free</title>
		<link>https://adamhorne.com/online-advertising-defending-free/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Adam Horne]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2019 19:39:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blog]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://adamhorne.com/?p=687</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Not since Guttenberg’s invention of the printing press has anything done so much to democratised media. From #BlackLivesMatter to The Arab Spring, good ideas, big ideas, can spread freely, all thanks to the free internet. OK. So let’s look at why “free” really is worth protecting. Even if that means championing online advertising. I promise [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><strong>Not since Guttenberg’s invention of the printing press has anything done so much to democratised media.</strong></p>



<p>From #BlackLivesMatter to The Arab Spring, good ideas, big ideas, can spread freely, all thanks to the free internet.</p>



<p>OK. So let’s look at why “free” really is worth protecting. Even if that means championing online advertising.</p>



<p>I promise this won’t hurt…</p>



<p>Before
 we assess the value of retargeted advertising, we need to rewind a 
little, and look at the relationship between marketers, and consumers, 
on the internet.</p>



<p>So let’s look at why “free” is worth protecting. I promise this won’t hurt&#8230;</p>



<p>Not
 since Guttenberg’s invention of the printing press has anything done so
 much to democratised media. From #BlackLivesMatter to The Arab Spring, 
good ideas, big ideas, can spread freely, all thanks to the free 
internet.</p>



<p><strong>That’s because the internet is best when it’s open to as many people as possible.</strong></p>



<p>For
 the vast majority of the internet, once you pay to access it (thru your
 phone company or ISPs monthly fee) it’s pretty much free to use. Search
 is free. Social media is free. News is free. Music is free. That’s not 
strictly true. You can pay for social media (LinkedIn Premium). You can 
pay for news (parts of premium publication like THe Economist and The 
Wall Street Journal are behind paywalls). And you can pay for Spotify to
 get rid of the ads that play between songs.</p>



<p>The free internet is largely paid for by advertising.</p>



<p><strong>So it’s not really free is it?</strong></p>



<p>What’s really happening is you’re paying for content on the internet with your attention.</p>



<p>For most people, this is a really good model.</p>



<p>It
 gives you access to insane levels of information. Want to know more 
about German trains? Well, thanks to free services like Google Search, 
industry publications about European trains, and blogs by trainspotters,
 and WikiPedia (with its donation / non-profit model) you can become an 
instant expert. You don’t need to pay to access professional 
publications.</p>



<p>This
 inclusivity gives the internet a network effect. That is, the more 
people contribute tweets, articles and entire websites about German 
trains, the more valuable the internet it is to everyone.</p>



<p>So free access to information is important.</p>



<p>&nbsp;How
 can advertising balance the needs of marketers to make money, in a way 
that is respectful to users, and might make their internet experience 
better?</p>



<p>&nbsp;By delivering relevant experiences.</p>



<p>Jeff Jarvis suggests, that advertising sucks on the internet, precisely because <a target="_blank" href="https://buzzmachine.com/2015/09/07/advertising-sucks-let-us-listicle-ways/" rel="noreferrer noopener">it isn’t relevant</a>.</p>



<p>I
 suggest that advertising retargeting, if done respectfully, and 
transparently, can be a very good. Good for both those that use it to 
market their products and services, and for consumers too.</p>



<p>Retargeting is a good start, but it’s still pretty dumb. Here’s why.</p>



<p>&nbsp;Let’s
 say you look at a pair of Levi’s jeans for sale on a website. Just 
once. That pair of jeans will mindlessly follow you around the web for 
weeks. What’s the half-life for the purchase of a pair of jeans? Maybe a
 week. So if you’ve not purchased new jeans a week after your first 
visit to an online jean retailer, there’s at least a 50% chance you’re 
not really in the market for jeans.</p>



<p>But no. You’ll be retargeted without mercy across the web.</p>



<p>When
 you’re bored at work and looking at fashion blogs? You’ll get an ad for
 jeans. When it’s raining and your car won’t start and you need to call a
 mechanic? It’s those jeans again. When you search for how to get red 
wine out of carpet? Yep. Jeans again… When your headache is so bad 
you’re looking into brain cancer symptoms? Jean ads…</p>



<p>This
 is a waste for everyone. For the consumer, it’s nauseating to see that 
same pair of jeans all the time. On the advertisers side, they’re paying
 for ad impressions that had almost zero chance of being clicked.</p>



<p>What
 would be better is if retargeting was coupled with other technologies 
(sentiment analysis and machine learning jump to mind). All with the aim
 to make the retargeting more relevant.</p>



<p>So,
 to use the examples above, perhaps the only good time to see that pair 
of jeans again was when you were bored at work and browsing fashion 
blogs. And perhaps the advertiser should have stayed away from 
mechanics, brain cancer and red wine stains…</p>



<p>And another reason why current retargeting is dumb?</p>



<p>Were
 you to buy those jeans, there’s still a good chance you’d see that ad 
for jeans, again. And an even better chance you’d want to burn down 
their jean factory!</p>



<p>So what things should the retargeting industry do to better balance their responsibilities to users?</p>



<ul><li>Always  anonymise personal data. Marketers should do everything to make this  data as abstract from a user’s identity as possible. It’s important to  know that I’m a man who loves volleyball, live in Stockholm, and am  looking to buy new black jeans. It’s not important for them to know my  date of birth, my passport number, or my name. They can market to me  knowing basic demographic and psychographic information</li><li>Encrypted  data when it’s at rest. In a world of endless hacking, leaks and  security compromises, users should expect all data about their web  browsing and purchase decisions be encrypted. So that when, not if, this  data falls into the wrong hands, it’s relatively safe</li><li>Treated  their practices transparently. Users have the right to know what data  is collected about them (their browsing habits and thus their  interests), why it’s being collected (to customise marketing messages),  and what the benefit is to the user (they get more relevant ads and they  get to use the internet for free</li><li>Make Opt-Outing easy.  It’s very important for users to have the option to opt out of  customised marketing experiences, and to receive generic marketing  messages. There’s a fraction of society that can’t compromise any level  of privacy for a better web experience. People in witness protection,  etc</li><li>Keep users best interest at heart. This is like the Hippocratic Oath Doctor’s take to “Do No Harm”</li></ul>



<p>&nbsp;These
 are all things that online marketing have, historically, been terrible 
at. They’ve commonly overstepped all reasonable privacy. They’ve had 
massive amounts of marketing data stolen. And perhaps most damaging of 
all to the marketing industry, they’ve never clearly articulated why 
they do any of this in a transparent way.</p>



<p>It matters. We need to get this right.</p>



<p><strong>For marketers it matters.</strong></p>



<ul><li>It matters that they to stop wasting money on useless ad impressions.</li><li>It matters they demand consumer attention when they’re useful to that consumer.</li><li>It matters that we move a higher percentage of consumer spending online.</li><li>It matters that we respect our customers.</li></ul>



<p><strong>And for consumers it matters.</strong></p>



<ul><li>It matters that the web stays free and open so that billions more people can join the conversation.</li><li>It matters that our attention isn’t wasted on stuff that can’t help us.</li><li>It matters that we have some control over our digital footprints.</li><li>It matters that the internet is fast and useful.</li><li>It matters that we stop seeing that God Damn jeans ad before we kill ourselves!</li></ul>



<p><em>Note:
 This is an essay I wrote defending web advertising (!!!) for Digital 
Analytics for Marketing Professionals course I took thru University of 
Illinois &amp; Coursera. It was originally published on <a target="_blank" href="https://www.linkedin.com/pulse/defending-free-adam-horne/" rel="noreferrer noopener">LinkedIn</a>.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Smoking: A Good Reason</title>
		<link>https://adamhorne.com/smoking-a-good-reason/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Adam Horne]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2019 19:37:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blog]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://adamhorne.com/?p=685</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I don’t smoke. But sometimes I wish I did. Smoking punctuates your day. A nicotine addiction makes you get up, go out, and then come back. When you return, it demands a new focus. When you work at a desk it’s very easy to get sucked into the rathole of what you’re doing. From researching [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><strong>I don’t smoke. But sometimes I wish I did.</strong></p>



<p>Smoking
 punctuates your day. A nicotine addiction makes you get up, go out, and
 then come back. When you return, it demands a new focus.</p>



<p>When
 you work at a desk it’s very easy to get sucked into the rathole of 
what you’re doing. From researching slightly-maybe-kind-of work related 
thing on Wikipedia, to spending hours redrawing a logo unnecessarily, 
there’s always something sucking away your time.</p>



<p>But
 not so much with the smokers I know. They waltz back from their 
cigarette break, clap their hands together and ask themselves what they 
should be doing right now.</p>



<p>They’d hate to hear it but they’re much more executive than the rest of us.</p>



<p>Smoking reminds me of the <a target="_blank" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pomodoro_Technique" rel="noreferrer noopener">Pomodoro Technique</a>.
 A clever little lifehack that suggests you slice up your day into a 
series of 20–25 minute bursts. It can be a useful way of ensuring you 
work on what matters most.</p>



<p>And smokers do it almost without thinking.</p>



<p>It’s a shame you can vape at your desk.</p>



<p>That would be the best of both worlds…</p>



<p>This originally appeared on <a target="_blank" href="http://cargocollective.com/adamhorne/filter/thinking/Smoking-A-Good-Reason" rel="noreferrer noopener">Medium</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Live Muzak: Transient culture and the hysterical search for authenticity</title>
		<link>https://adamhorne.com/live-muzak-transient-culture-and-the-hysterical-search-for-authenticity/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Adam Horne]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2019 19:31:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blog]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://adamhorne.com/?p=678</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I went to We Love Green&#160;on the weekend. A music festival in a beautiful Parisian park that, I kid you not, is usually full of peacocks. I was certainly among the older members of the oh-so-chic, not-so-chalant crowd. And it got me thinking about how the radical changes in how music is distributed and consumed [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><strong>I went to </strong><a rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank" href="http://www.welovegreen.fr/"><strong>We Love Green</strong></a><strong>&nbsp;on  the weekend. A music festival in a beautiful Parisian park that, I kid  you not, is usually full of peacocks. I was certainly among the older  members of the oh-so-chic, not-so-chalant crowd. And it got me thinking  about how the radical changes in how music is distributed and consumed  has had some pretty big changes to live music.</strong></p>



<p><strong><em>It used to be different.</em></strong></p>



<p>In
 the 1990&#8217;s your music was your tribe. Your identity. It’s how you told 
your peers, and perhaps more importantly, it was like your own personal 
muse, consistently illuminating your values to yourself. Your chosen 
genre became your tribe. It defines your identity. An identity that 
didn’t deviate to neighbouring musical styles. Hip-Hop guys. Grunge 
guys. Metal Guys. All different.</p>



<p>Music
 festivals in the 1990&#8217;s started to do the genre hopping so we didn’t 
need to. It was expensive, and hard to get full line-ups of just Hip-Hop
 to places like Perth for example, so mixing established and emerging 
genres become <em>de rigueur</em>. That made it easy for hardcore genre 
fans to enjoy the other without having to compromise their integrity. 
But honesty, most live music was big acts being opened by little acts, 
all within the same musical genre.</p>



<p>Then
 music changed towards the end of the 1990&#8217;s. You know this story. It 
changed because distribution from artificial scarcity to managing 
abundance. It went from $A29.95 Compact Discs that were artificially 
high (and at the time pretty hard to copy) to being something you copied
 as free digital files with your friends both online and offline. Then 
the iPod. All leading to a generation of music fans who could genre-hop 
because of the sheer abundance of free music at their fingertips. Music 
become a commodity. Then it became air; everywhere and free. So that’s 
good for normal people right…</p>



<p><strong><em>And now?</em></strong></p>



<p>So here are some things I noticed about live music today.</p>



<p>I
 saw one kid in a band t-shirt. One. A white Run-D.M.C. tee on a girl. 
Selected to complete a rather fetching ensemble, I suspect, and to very 
good effect. Just part of the look. A semiotic cultural reference, an 
icon, not an identity or affinity. But fuck, at least she wore a band 
t-shirt to a music festival.</p>



<p>Live
 music, and its accompanying conventions really have failed to keep up 
in this schizophrenic attention economy that the internet propagated. 
Forty minutes between acts on the main stage? You’re killing me. Sound 
checking your drums again? And they still work. Now you’re killing your 
industry. Seriously.</p>



<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="alignleft"><img loading="lazy" width="600" height="600" src="https://adamhorne.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/1_YYkoWoTNkHnOncs5qO8Gdw.jpeg" alt="" class="wp-image-681" srcset="https://adamhorne.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/1_YYkoWoTNkHnOncs5qO8Gdw.jpeg 600w, https://adamhorne.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/1_YYkoWoTNkHnOncs5qO8Gdw-150x150.jpeg 150w, https://adamhorne.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/1_YYkoWoTNkHnOncs5qO8Gdw-300x300.jpeg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px" /><figcaption>“Hands up with #welovegreen #orderofneverhide <a href="http://pic.twitter.com/37HLFg7G8">pic.twitter.com/37HLFg7G8</a>&#8221; Via <a href="https://twitter.com/KenzaSMG">@KenzaSMG</a></figcaption></figure></div>



<p>Most of the acts seemed a little too accepting to be the muzak to big picnic in the park. No one fought for my attention like <em>The Darkness</em>&nbsp;might, or like <em>Peaches</em>&nbsp;might, or <em>Björk</em>&nbsp;might.
 That sheer insistence on connecting just wasn’t there. Replaced with a 
nervous irony. I love irony, just don‘t hide behind it.</p>



<p>I
 didn’t really feel a connection, a holy (or unholy) unity between me, 
the people, the music and the musicians. No one believed it. Just, 
nothing.</p>



<p>Conventional 
wisdom holds that the money in music is now in the delivery of live 
music. So they really need to start fighting harder for my conspicuous 
consumption.</p>



<p>Lines for the toilets are still the only really memorable part of your day.</p>



<p>I
 didn’t see one video screen at the festival because there weren&#8217;t any. 
Which meant about 5% of people were close enough to see what was 
happening on stage. All I could see were some rather vulnerable looking 
people whose stagecraft didn’t seem to make it thru customs.</p>



<p>There’s
 a lot more young French girls in attendance than French guys. Maybe 
young French women define their identity by a much wider range of 
cultural consumption. Because you don’t come here for the music. You 
come here for the organic food and the selfies.</p>



<p>Mobile
 phone reception (or lack thereof) could kill festivals. Reception is so
 bad, cell towers so overloaded that during a music festival it requires
 the patience of a saint to post that selfie, tweet that #hashtag, or 
send a text to your friend who couldn’t make it. The humble brag is just
 too hard. So if I can’t tell anyone just how much fun you’re having 
right now, at this exact moment, is it worth enjoying this moment right 
now?&nbsp;<em>“Sorry, just. Trying. To get reception. What did you say? Who’s playing? Do I know this song?”</em></p>



<p>The
 acts generally use a stylistically limited palette of synth sounds. 
Sounds that reference the aesthetic of 1980&#8217;s pop music. But not the 
song-craft, ethos or ideology of 80&#8217;s pop. They forgot the important 
bit. Sounds without meanings. A fashionistas soundstage that belies a 
central artistic anxiety — in a world where you can click, swipe and 
jump to anything at any time,&nbsp;<em>what exactly do you want from us?</em></p>



<p>This originally appeared on <a target="_blank" href="https://medium.com/@adamhorne/live-muzak-118c23a99e0d" rel="noreferrer noopener">Medium</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Advertising &#038; AI: Awarded Intelligence</title>
		<link>https://adamhorne.com/advertising-ai-awarded-intelligence/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Adam Horne]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2019 11:39:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blog]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://adamhorne.com/?p=343</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Imagine this.

You’re at the Cannes Lions International Festival for Creativity. In about 10 years. As champagne flows and flows, rumours grow and grow. Finally it’s discovered that the Grand Prix winning campaign was created by an artificial intelligence system.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><strong>Imagine this.<br> You’re at the Cannes Lions International Festival for Creativity. In about 10 years. As champagne flows and flows, rumours grow and grow. Finally it’s discovered that the Grand Prix winning campaign was created by an artificial intelligence system.</strong></p>



<p>What happens then?</p>



<p>Do they disqualify the campaign — like a cyborg would be disqualified at the Olympics?</p>



<p>Does the planning department get the award?<br>
They were the people that asked the right questions to get the right answers.</p>



<p>Do the Creative Directors win the award?<br>
They chose to action the concept the system conceived.</p>



<p>Do the software developers win?<br>
They made the thing, that made the thing, that won the award.</p>



<p>The real question isn’t if this will happen, but when this will happen.</p>



<p>Because our world has become a world where artificial intelligence and deep learning breakthroughs are the new Moore’s Law.<br>
Art direction, blue. Copywriting, green. Creative technologist, red. Strategic planning, yellow.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image alignfull"><img loading="lazy" width="2667" height="1500" src="https://adamhorne.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/data-center-google.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-344" srcset="https://adamhorne.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/data-center-google.jpg 2667w, https://adamhorne.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/data-center-google-300x169.jpg 300w, https://adamhorne.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/data-center-google-768x432.jpg 768w, https://adamhorne.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/data-center-google-1024x576.jpg 1024w, https://adamhorne.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/data-center-google-1568x882.jpg 1568w" sizes="(max-width: 2667px) 100vw, 2667px" /></figure>



<p>Art direction, blue. Copywriting, green. Creative technologist, red. Strategic planning, yellow.</p>



<p>From speculative stuff like IBM’s Watson, Google’s DeepMind and Facebook’s DeepFace, to consumer facing things like Apple’s Siri or Google Now, innovation gallops ahead.</p>



<p>We should stop thinking about creativity as a uniquely human vocation. It’s hubristic and arrogant at best, and prideful and ignorant at worst.</p>



<p>Creativity is just a new combination of existing things. And that sounds like something a system could get better at over time…</p>



<p>We need, as an industry that’s champions the power of ideas, as an advertising industry, to keep that in mind.</p>



<p>A lot of people might find this future to be cold and oppressive. But think about the potential for big, new ideas to be developed.</p>



<p>A future that, ironically, thanks to computer systems, is more humane, and beautiful, because of those systems.</p>



<p>But not everything will change.</p>



<p>There will always be champagne at Cannes…</p>



<p>This originally appeared on Medium.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
